James Goh MEcon BEC

Full-Stacked Coding | Sales & Marketing | Business Intelligence | Logistics

■(801)-897-6322 ■jgoh1994@gmail.com ■ https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesbbgoh/ ■https://github.com/jgohbb

Diverse logistics, commercial sales, marketing and analysis experience; project skills in capital management and strategic company initiatives; cross cultural proficiency from assignments in Europe, Canada, USA, Asia and Australia; qualifications in economics, finance, supply chain and full-stacked coding. Ready for entry-level software development position leveraging on commercial experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rio Tinto Copper & Diamonds, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA

Commercial Executive, 2015 - 2018

Managed the sales of precious metals and sulfuric acid with an annual turnover of \$350M.. Role included liaising with operations and customers, enhancing business systems, providing business solutions and analysis to improve market position and achieve strategic sales targets. Developed consolidated database systems for tracking and optimizing the execution of sales by linking commodity prices to contracts.

Rio Tinto Copper Group Marketing, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA

Senior Analyst, 2010 - 2015

Managed team in SLC with responsibility for global and regional marketing analysis and reporting; provided market research and intelligence to the sales team and Rio Tinto groups; developed corporate strategic initiatives to lower cost and grow revenue. Streamlined and automated marketing database which reduce redundancy by 30 percent, improve clarity and facilitate optimal sales decision-making.

Docomo Intertouch, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada

Business Development Manager, 2009 – 2010

Technology based subsidiary of telecommunications conglomerate NTT Docomo, Japan. Reported to CEO base in Singapore, responsibilities included establishing sales and marketing operations in Canada and assessing M&A opportunities in North America.

Rio Tinto Copper Projects, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada

Project Consultant, 2008 – 2009

Developed strategy and implementation plans to manage intellectual property; created manpower database for the greenfield Oyu Tolgoi copper project in Mongolia.

Rio Tinto Minerals, London, England, Great Britain

European Logistics Business & Finance Manager, 2006 – 2008; European Logistics Manager, 2002 – 2006 Held various supply chain management positions in Europe, overseeing supply chain strategies, budget and forecasting, financial management, project analysis, European regulatory issues on waste materials and systems implementation (SAP).

EDUCATION

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE Master of Social Sciences (Economics)
UNIVERSITY OF WESTERN AUSTRALIA Bachelor of Economics
MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Executive Training on Supply Chain
MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Artificial Intelligence course
UNIVERSITY OF UTAH Full-Stacked Coding Bootcamp

SKILLS

Javascript, JQuery, HTML, Bootstrap, JSON, API, Firebase, MySQL, MogoDB, React, GitHub, Bash, VSCode, Heroku, Laravel PHP, Express, MERN Stack.

Lean–Six Sigma (Green Belt 2012), Negotiation & Influencing - ENS International (2001, 2008, 2016), Marketing Academy course – IMD International Institute UK 2012.